{
    "UserManagement": {
        "usersandgroups": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command do you use to run as root?",
            "quizAnswer": "sudo"
        },
        "usermanagementtools": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command is used to change a password?",
            "quizAnswer": "passwd"
        },
        "rootuser": {
            "quizQuestion": "What file shows the users who have access to sudo?",
            "quizAnswer": "/etc/sudoers"
        },
        "etcpasswdfile": {
            "quizQuestion": "If a user doesn't have login access how is that denoted in /etc/passwd?",
            "quizAnswer": "*"
        },
        "etcgroupfile": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the GID of root?",
            "quizAnswer": "0"
        }
    },
    "TheFilesystem": {
        "symlinks": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the command used to make a symlink?",
            "quizAnswer": "ln -s"
        },
        "swapspace": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the command to enable swap space on a device?",
            "quizAnswer": "swapon"
        },
        "mountingandunmountingfilesystems": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command is used to attach a filesystem?",
            "quizAnswer": "mount"
        },
        "inodes": {
            "quizQuestion": "How do you see how many inodes are left on your system?",
            "quizAnswer": "df -i"
        },
        "filesystemtypes": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the common Linux filesystem type?",
            "quizAnswer": "ext4"
        },
        "filesystemrepair": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command is used to check the integrity of a filesystem?",
            "quizAnswer": "fsck"
        },
        "filesystemhierarchy": {
            "quizQuestion": "What directory is used to store logs?",
            "quizAnswer": "/var"
        },
        "etcfstabfilesystemtable": {
            "quizQuestion": "What file is used to define how filesystems should be mounted?",
            "quizAnswer": "/etc/fstab"
        },
        "diskusage": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command is use to show how much space is free on your disk?",
            "quizAnswer": "df"
        },
        "diskpartitioning": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the parted command to make a partition?",
            "quizAnswer": "mkpart"
        },
        "creatingfilesystems": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command is used to create a filesystem?",
            "quizAnswer": "mkfs"
        },
        "anatomyofadisk": {
            "quizQuestion": "What partition type is used to create more than 4 partitions in the MBR partitioning scheme?",
            "quizAnswer": "extended"
        }
    },
    "TextFu": {
        "uniquniquecommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command would you use to remove duplicates in a file?",
            "quizAnswer": "uniq"
        },
        "trtranslatecommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command is used to translate characters?",
            "quizAnswer": "tr"
        },
        "tailcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the flag used to follow a file in tail?",
            "quizAnswer": "-f"
        },
        "stdoutstandardoutredirect": {
            "quizQuestion": "What redirector do you use to append output to a file?",
            "quizAnswer": ">>"
        },
        "stdinstandardinredirect": {
            "quizQuestion": "What redirector do you use to redirect stdin?",
            "quizAnswer": "<"
        },
        "stderrstandarderrorredirect": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the redirector for stderr?",
            "quizAnswer": "2>"
        },
        "sortcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What flag do you use to do a reverse sort?",
            "quizAnswer": "-r"
        },
        "pipeteeredirect": {
            "quizQuestion": "What key represents the pipe operator?",
            "quizAnswer": "|"
        },
        "pastecommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What flag do you use with paste to make everything go on one line?",
            "quizAnswer": "-s"
        },
        "nlwccommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command would you use to get the total number of words in a file and just the words?",
            "quizAnswer": "wc -w"
        },
        "joinsplitcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command would you use to join files named cat dog cow?",
            "quizAnswer": "join cat dog cow"
        },
        "headcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What flag would you use to change the number of lines you want to view for the head command?",
            "quizAnswer": "-n"
        },
        "grepcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command do you use to find a certain pattern?",
            "quizAnswer": "grep"
        },
        "expandunexpandcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command is used to convert TABs to spaces?",
            "quizAnswer": "expand"
        },
        "envenvironment": {
            "quizQuestion": "How do you see your environment variables?",
            "quizAnswer": "env"
        },
        "cutcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command would you use to get the first character of every line in a file?",
            "quizAnswer": "cut -c 1"
        }
    },
    "Subnetting": {
        "subnettingcheats": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the binary conversion of 123?",
            "quizAnswer": "1111011"
        },
        "subnets": {
            "quizQuestion": "True or false, a subnet consists of a subnet mask and network prefix.",
            "quizAnswer": "true"
        },
        "subnetmath": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the binary equivalent of 255?",
            "quizAnswer": "11111111"
        },
        "natnetworkaddresstranslation": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is used to represent a single private address to the Internet?",
            "quizAnswer": "NAT"
        },
        "ipv6": {
            "quizQuestion": "What IP address is used to help increase the number of hosts that can connect to the Internet?",
            "quizAnswer": "IPv6"
        },
        "ipv4": {
            "quizQuestion": "How many bytes are in an IPv4 address?",
            "quizAnswer": "4"
        }
    },
    "Routing": {
        "whatisarouter": {
            "quizQuestion": "How do packets measure distance?",
            "quizAnswer": "hops"
        },
        "routingtable": {
            "quizQuestion": "Where are packets routed to if our routing table doesn't know?",
            "quizAnswer": "gateway"
        },
        "routingprotocols": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the term used when all routing tables know the network topology?",
            "quizAnswer": "convergence"
        },
        "pathofapacket": {
            "quizQuestion": "How do we find the MAC address of an IP address?",
            "quizAnswer": "ARP"
        },
        "linkstateprotocols": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is one of the most common link state protocols?",
            "quizAnswer": "OSPF"
        },
        "distancevectorprotocols": {
            "quizQuestion": "True or false, distance protocols use the route with the least amount of bandwidth?",
            "quizAnswer": "false"
        },
        "bgpbordergatewayprotocol": {
            "quizQuestion": "What protocol basically makes the Internet work?",
            "quizAnswer": "BGP"
        }
    },
    "Processes": {
        "procfilesystem": {
            "quizQuestion": "What filesystem stores process information?",
            "quizAnswer": "/proc"
        },
        "processtermination": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the most common termination status for a process succeeding?",
            "quizAnswer": "0"
        },
        "processstates": {
            "quizQuestion": "What STAT code is used to represent an uninterruptible sleep?",
            "quizAnswer": "D"
        },
        "processsignals": {
            "quizQuestion": "What signal is unblockable?",
            "quizAnswer": "SIGKILL"
        },
        "processniceness": {
            "quizQuestion": "If I want a process to get more CPU priority, do I use a lower or higher nice number?",
            "quizAnswer": "lower"
        },
        "processdetails": {
            "quizQuestion": "What manages and controls processes?",
            "quizAnswer": "kernel"
        },
        "processcreation": {
            "quizQuestion": "What system call creates a new process?",
            "quizAnswer": "fork"
        },
        "monitorprocessespscommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What ps flag is used to view detailed information about processes?",
            "quizAnswer": "u"
        },
        "killingprocesses": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the signal name for the default kill command?",
            "quizAnswer": "SIGTERM"
        },
        "jobcontrol": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command is used to list background jobs?",
            "quizAnswer": "jobs"
        },
        "controllingterminal": {
            "quizQuestion": "What value is given for a process that does not have a controlling terminal?",
            "quizAnswer": "?"
        }
    },
    "ProcessUtilization": {
        "trackingprocessestop": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command displays the same output as the first line in top?",
            "quizAnswer": "uptime"
        },
        "trackingprocesseslsoffuser": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command is used to list open files and their process information?",
            "quizAnswer": "lsof"
        },
        "processthreads": {
            "quizQuestion": "True or false, all processes start out single-threaded.",
            "quizAnswer": "true"
        },
        "memorymonitoring": {
            "quizQuestion": "What tool is used to view memory utilization?",
            "quizAnswer": "vmstat"
        },
        "iomonitoring": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command can be used to view I/O and CPU usage?",
            "quizAnswer": "iostat"
        },
        "cronjobs": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the command to edit your cronjobs?",
            "quizAnswer": "crontab -e"
        },
        "cpumonitoring": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command can you use to see the load average?",
            "quizAnswer": "uptime"
        },
        "continuousmonitoring": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is a good tool to use for monitoring system resources?",
            "quizAnswer": "sar"
        }
    },
    "Permissions": {
        "umask": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command is used to change default file permissions?",
            "quizAnswer": "umask"
        },
        "stickybit": {
            "quizQuestion": "What symbol represents the sticky bit?",
            "quizAnswer": "t"
        },
        "setuidsetuserid": {
            "quizQuestion": "What number represents the SUID?",
            "quizAnswer": "4"
        },
        "setgidsetgroupid": {
            "quizQuestion": "What number represents the SGID?",
            "quizAnswer": "2"
        },
        "processpermissions": {
            "quizQuestion": "What UID decides what access to grant?",
            "quizAnswer": "effective"
        },
        "ownershippermissions": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command do you use to change user ownership?",
            "quizAnswer": "chown"
        },
        "modifyingpermissions": {
            "quizQuestion": "What number represents the read permission when using numerical format?",
            "quizAnswer": "4"
        },
        "filepermissions": {
            "quizQuestion": "What permission bit is used for executable?",
            "quizAnswer": "x"
        }
    },
    "Packages": {
        "packagerepositories": {
            "quizQuestion": "Where is the sources file in a Debian system?",
            "quizAnswer": "/etc/apt/sources.list"
        },
        "packagemanagementsystems": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command is used to show package information on a Debian system?",
            "quizAnswer": "apt show"
        },
        "packageinstalltools": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the package management tool for .deb files?",
            "quizAnswer": "dpkg"
        },
        "compressedarchivestar": {
            "quizQuestion": "What tar flag is used to create archives?",
            "quizAnswer": "c"
        },
        "compilesourcecode": {
            "quizQuestion": "What should you use instead of make install ALWAYS?",
            "quizAnswer": "checkinstall"
        }
    },
    "NetworkTroubleshooting": {
        "traceroute": {
            "quizQuestion": "What gets decremented by one when making hops across the network?",
            "quizAnswer": "ttl"
        },
        "ping": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the roundtrip time unit of measurement?",
            "quizAnswer": "ms"
        },
        "packetanalysis": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the flag to capture a specific interface with tcpdump?",
            "quizAnswer": "-i"
        },
        "netstat": {
            "quizQuestion": "What port is used for HTTPS?",
            "quizAnswer": "443"
        },
        "icmp": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the ICMP type for echo request?",
            "quizAnswer": "8"
        }
    },
    "NetworkSharing": {
        "simplehttpserver": {
            "quizQuestion": "What tool can you use to create a simple http server with python?",
            "quizAnswer": "SimpleHTTPServer"
        },
        "samba": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the latest protocol used for file transfer between Windows and Linux?",
            "quizAnswer": "cifs"
        },
        "rsync": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command would be useful for data backups?",
            "quizAnswer": "rsync"
        },
        "nfsnetworkfileshare": {
            "quizQuestion": "What tool is used to manage mount points automatically?",
            "quizAnswer": "automount"
        },
        "networkfilesharing": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command can you use to securely copy files from one host to another?",
            "quizAnswer": "scp"
        }
    },
    "NetworkConfig": {
        "route": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the command flag to delete a route?",
            "quizAnswer": "del"
        },
        "networkmanager": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the command to view NetworkManager information?",
            "quizAnswer": "nm-tool"
        },
        "networkinterfaces": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the command to configure our network interfaces?",
            "quizAnswer": "ifconfig"
        },
        "dhclient": {
            "quizQuestion": "What tries to assign IP addresses with the DHCP protocol?",
            "quizAnswer": "dhclient"
        },
        "arpcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command can you use to view your ARP cache?",
            "quizAnswer": "arp"
        }
    },
    "NetworkBasics": {
        "transportlayer": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is a reliable transport protocol?",
            "quizAnswer": "TCP"
        },
        "tcpipmodel": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the top layer of the TCP/IP model?",
            "quizAnswer": "application"
        },
        "osimodel": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is used as the theoretical model of networking?",
            "quizAnswer": "OSI"
        },
        "networklayer": {
            "quizQuestion": "What are smaller networks that make up the Internet called?",
            "quizAnswer": "subnets"
        },
        "networkbasics": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the local area network known as?",
            "quizAnswer": "LAN"
        },
        "networkaddressing": {
            "quizQuestion": "How many bytes are in an IPv4 address?",
            "quizAnswer": "4"
        },
        "linklayer": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is used to find the MAC address on the same network?",
            "quizAnswer": "ARP"
        },
        "dhcpoverview": {
            "quizQuestion": "What are the steps in a DHCP request?",
            "quizAnswer": "discover, offer, request, ack"
        },
        "applicationlayer": {
            "quizQuestion": "What layer is used to present the packet data in a user friendly format?",
            "quizAnswer": "application"
        }
    },
    "Logging": {
        "systemlogging": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the daemon that manages log on newer Linux systems?",
            "quizAnswer": "rsyslogd"
        },
        "syslog": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command can you use to manually log a message?",
            "quizAnswer": "logger"
        },
        "managinglogfiles": {
            "quizQuestion": "What utility is used to manage logs?",
            "quizAnswer": "logrotate"
        },
        "kernellogging": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command can be used to view kernel bootup messages?",
            "quizAnswer": "dmesg"
        },
        "generallogging": {
            "quizQuestion": "What log file logs everything except auth messages?",
            "quizAnswer": "syslog"
        },
        "authenticationlogging": {
            "quizQuestion": "What log is used for user authentication?",
            "quizAnswer": "auth.log"
        }
    },
    "Kernel": {
        "systemcalls": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is used to switch from user mode to kernel mode?",
            "quizAnswer": "system call"
        },
        "kernelprivilegelevels": {
            "quizQuestion": "What ring number has the highest privileges?",
            "quizAnswer": "0"
        },
        "kerneloverview": {
            "quizQuestion": "What level of the operating system manages devices?",
            "quizAnswer": "kernel"
        },
        "kernelmodules": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command is used to unload a module?",
            "quizAnswer": "modprobe -r"
        },
        "kernellocation": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the kernel image called in /boot?",
            "quizAnswer": "vmlinuz"
        },
        "kernelinstallation": {
            "quizQuestion": "How do you see the kernel version of your system?",
            "quizAnswer": "uname -r"
        }
    },
    "Init": {
        "upstartoverview": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the init implementation that is used by Ubuntu?",
            "quizAnswer": "Upstart"
        },
        "upstartjobs": {
            "quizQuestion": "How would I manually restart an Upstart job called peanuts?",
            "quizAnswer": "sudo initctl restart peanuts"
        },
        "sysvservices": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the command to stop a service named peanut with Sys V?",
            "quizAnswer": "sudo service peanut stop"
        },
        "sysvoverview": {
            "quizQuestion": "What runlevel is usually used for shutdown?",
            "quizAnswer": "0"
        },
        "systemdoverview": {
            "quizQuestion": "What unit is used to group together other units?",
            "quizAnswer": "target"
        },
        "systemdgoals": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the command to start a service named peanut.service?",
            "quizAnswer": "sudo systemctl start peanut.service"
        },
        "powerstates": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the command to poweroff your system in 4 minutes?",
            "quizAnswer": "sudo shutdown -h +4"
        }
    },
    "GettingStarted": {
        "ubuntu": {
            "quizQuestion": "What operating system is Ubuntu based off of?",
            "quizAnswer": "Debian"
        },
        "redhatenterpriselinux": {
            "quizQuestion": "What package manager does RHEL use?",
            "quizAnswer": "RPM"
        },
        "openSUSE": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the name of openSUSE's Administration/Installation Tool?",
            "quizAnswer": "YaST"
        },
        "linuxmint": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is Linux Mint based off of?",
            "quizAnswer": "Ubuntu"
        },
        "linuxhistory": {
            "quizQuestion": "Who developed the Linux kernel?",
            "quizAnswer": "Linus Torvalds"
        },
        "gentoo": {
            "quizQuestion": "What package management system does Gentoo use?",
            "quizAnswer": "portage"
        },
        "fedora": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is RHEL branched off of?",
            "quizAnswer": "Fedora"
        },
        "debian": {
            "quizQuestion": "What kind of release does Testing and Unstable have?",
            "quizAnswer": "rolling"
        },
        "archlinux": {
            "quizQuestion": "What package manager does Arch Linux use?",
            "quizAnswer": "pacman"
        }
    },
    "Dns": {
        "whatisdns": {
            "quizQuestion": "True or false, DNS helps us find MAC addresses for hostnames?",
            "quizAnswer": "false"
        },
        "etchosts": {
            "quizQuestion": "What file is used to map hostnames to IP addresses on our machines?",
            "quizAnswer": "/etc/hosts"
        },
        "dnstools": {
            "quizQuestion": "What tool is used to get detailed information about DNS name servers?",
            "quizAnswer": "dig"
        },
        "dnssetup": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the de facto DNS server for Linux?",
            "quizAnswer": "BIND"
        },
        "dnsprocess": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the abbreviation for the nameservers where .com, .net, .org, etc addresses are found?",
            "quizAnswer": "TLD"
        },
        "dnscomponents": {
            "quizQuestion": "What resource record type is used for mail exchangers?",
            "quizAnswer": "MX"
        }
    },
    "Devices": {
        "udev": {
            "quizQuestion": "What dynamically adds and removes devices?",
            "quizAnswer": "udev"
        },
        "sysfs": {
            "quizQuestion": "What directory is used to view detailed information on devices?",
            "quizAnswer": "/sys"
        },
        "listingdevices": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command can be used to view usb devices?",
            "quizAnswer": "lsusb"
        },
        "devicetypes": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the symbol for character devices in the ls -l command?",
            "quizAnswer": "c"
        },
        "devicenames": {
            "quizQuestion": "What would commonly be the device name for the first partition on the second SCSI disk?",
            "quizAnswer": "sdb1"
        },
        "devdirectory": {
            "quizQuestion": "Where are device files stored on the system?",
            "quizAnswer": "/dev"
        },
        "ddcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the dd option for block size?",
            "quizAnswer": "bs"
        }
    },
    "CommandLine": {
        "whatiscommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command can you use to see a small description of a command?",
            "quizAnswer": "whatis"
        },
        "touchcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "How do you create a file called myfile?",
            "quizAnswer": "touch myfile"
        },
        "theshell": {
            "quizQuestion": "What should be outputted to the display when you type echo Hello World?",
            "quizAnswer": "Hello World"
        },
        "printworkingdirectorypwdcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "How do I find what directory you are currently in?",
            "quizAnswer": "pwd"
        },
        "movemvcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "How do you rename a file called cat to dog?",
            "quizAnswer": "mv cat dog"
        },
        "mancommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "How do you see the manuals for a command?",
            "quizAnswer": "man"
        },
        "makedirectorymkdircommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command is use to make a directory?",
            "quizAnswer": "mkdir"
        },
        "listdirectorieslscommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command would you use to see hidden files?",
            "quizAnswer": "ls -a"
        },
        "lesscommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "How do you quit out of a less command?",
            "quizAnswer": "q"
        },
        "historycommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the command to clear the terminal?",
            "quizAnswer": "clear"
        },
        "helpcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "How do you get quick command line help for built-in bash commands?",
            "quizAnswer": "help"
        },
        "findcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What option should I specify for find if I want to search by name?",
            "quizAnswer": "-name"
        },
        "filecommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command can you use to find the file type of a file?",
            "quizAnswer": "file"
        },
        "exitcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "How can you exit from the shell?",
            "quizAnswer": "exit"
        },
        "copycpcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What flag do you need to specify to copy over a directory?",
            "quizAnswer": "-r"
        },
        "changedirectorycdcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "If you are in /home/pete/Pictures and wanted to go to /home/pete, whatâ€™s a good shortcut to use?",
            "quizAnswer": "cd .."
        },
        "catcommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What's a good way to see the contents of a file?",
            "quizAnswer": "cat"
        },
        "aliascommand": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command is used to make an alias?",
            "quizAnswer": "alias"
        }
    },
    "BootTheSystem": {
        "bootprocessoverview": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the last stage in the Linux boot process?",
            "quizAnswer": "init"
        },
        "bootprocesskernel": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is used in modern systems to load up a temporary root filesystem?",
            "quizAnswer": "initramfs"
        },
        "bootprocessinit": {
            "quizQuestion": "What is the newest standard for init?",
            "quizAnswer": "systemd"
        },
        "bootprocessbootloader": {
            "quizQuestion": "What kernel parameter makes it so you don't see bootup messages?",
            "quizAnswer": "quiet"
        },
        "bootprocessbios": {
            "quizQuestion": "What does the BIOS load?",
            "quizAnswer": "bootloader"
        }
    },
    "AdvancedTextFu": {
        "vimsearchpatterns": {
            "quizQuestion": "What key is used to search in vim?",
            "quizAnswer": "/"
        },
        "vimsavingandexiting": {
            "quizQuestion": "How do you quit out of vim without saving?",
            "quizAnswer": ":q!"
        },
        "vimnavigation": {
            "quizQuestion": "What letter is used to move down?",
            "quizAnswer": "j"
        },
        "viminsertingappendingtext": {
            "quizQuestion": "What key is use to insert text before the cursor?",
            "quizAnswer": "i"
        },
        "vimediting": {
            "quizQuestion": "What character is used to delete an entire line?",
            "quizAnswer": "dd"
        },
        "regularexpressionsregex": {
            "quizQuestion": "What regular expression would you use to match a single character?",
            "quizAnswer": "."
        },
        "emacsmanipulatefiles": {
            "quizQuestion": "What command is used to open a file?",
            "quizAnswer": "C-x C-f"
        },
        "emacsexitingandhelp": {
            "quizQuestion": "How do you access the help menu?",
            "quizAnswer": "C-h C-h"
        },
        "emacsediting": {
            "quizQuestion": "How do you move to the end of the buffer?",
            "quizAnswer": "M->"
        },
        "emacsbuffernavigation": {
            "quizQuestion": "How do you kill a buffer?",
            "quizAnswer": "C-x k"
        }
    }
}
